Otto Klemperer Archive
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Klemperer Film Materials, 1885-1972 (Box 53-100, 106-108)
  - Writings (Box 53)
    - Klemperer, Otto. Meine Erinnerungen an Gustav Mahler. (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Klemperer, Otto. Rede gehalten am Bankett zu Ehren des 50jaehrigen Bestehens des Philharmonischen Chores am 5. Dezember 1932. (Box-folder 53/7)
    - Legge, Walter. Klemperer. (Box-folder 53/8)
    - Sessions, Roger. Otto Klemperer. (Box-folder 53/9)
  - Interviews (Box 53-55)
    Contains typescripts and photocopies of typescripts of interviews with and about Otto Klemperer, in English and German.
    Arranged alphabetically by interviewee or interviewer.
    - Interviews with Otto Klemperer
      - Bregstein, Philo. Band I-IV (Box-folder 53/10)
      - Bregstein, Philo. Band V-VIII and X (Box-folder 53/11)
      - Freeman, John (Box-folder 53/12)
      - Heyworth, Peter, In English. (Box-folder 53/13)
      - Heyworth, Peter, In German. (Box-folder 53/14)
    - Interviews about Otto Klemperer
      - Andras, Miko (Box-folder 54/1)
      - Asser-Mengelberg, Nora (Box-folder 54/2)
      - Bahrwahser, Hubert (Box-folder 54/3)
      - Baracs, [?] (Box-folder 54/4)
      - Bloch, Ernst (Box-folder 54/5)
      - Blum, Thomas (Box-folder 54/6)
      - Boulez, Pierre (Box-folder 54/7)
      - Bresser, Jan (Box-folder 54/8)
      - Byrnes, Harold (Box-folder 54/9)
      - Clark, [?] (Box-folder 54/10)
      - Cronheim, Paul (Box-folder 54/11)
      - Curjel, Hans (Box-folder 54/12)
      - David, Lisl (Box-folder 54/13)
      - Dessau, Paul (Box-folder 54/14)
      - Downes, E. (Box-folder 54/15)
      - Eisler, Georg (Box-folder 54/16)
      - Ernster, Dezsö (Box-folder 54/17)
      - Faber, Lothar (Box-folder 54/18)
      - Farjon, Mies (Box-folder 54/19)
      - Felsenstein, Walter (Box-folder 54/20)
      - Feuchtwanger, Marta (Box-folder 54/21)
      - Fischer, Sandra (Box-folder 54/22)
      - Flothuis, Marius (Box-folder 54/23)
      - Forbach, Moje (Box-folder 54/24)
      - Freudenthal, Otto (Box-folder 54/25)
      - Grub, Suvi Raj (Box-folder 54/26)
      - Grün-Kortner, Marianne (Box-folder 54/27)
      - Harewood, Lord (Box-folder 54/28)
      - Heyworth, Peter (Box-folder 54/29)
      - Hofmüller, Max (Box-folder 54/30)
      - Jelinek, J. (Box-folder 55/1)
      - Juhasz, Sari (Box-folder 55/2)
      - Kappeyne, [?] (Box-folder 55/3)
      - Klemperer, Lotte (Box-folder 55/4)
      - Klemperer, Werner (Box-folder 55/5)
      - Kruttge, Eigel (Box-folder 55/6)
      - Kubelik, Rafael (Box-folder 55/7)
      - Kun, Imre (Box-folder 55/8)
      - Kuphal, F. (Box-folder 55/9)
      - Leeuwen, Van (Box-folder 55/10)
      - Lehman, Lotte (Box-folder 55/11)
      - Machat, E. (Box-folder 55/12)
      - Mann, Katja (Box-folder 55/13)
      - Metz, Louis (Box-folder 55/14)
      - Morris, [?] (Box-folder 55/15)
      - Novotná, Jarmila (Box-folder 55/16)
      - Parikian, Manoug (Box-folder 55/17)
      - Pella, Paul (Box-folder 55/18)
      - Pollak, [?] (Box-folder 55/19)
      - Reichenfeld, Adam (Box-folder 55/20)
      - Reinhardt, Gottfried (Box-folder 55/21)
      - Reiss, [?] (Box-folder 55/22)
      - Plessner, [Helmuth] (Box-folder 55/23)
      - Sándor, Judith (Box-folder 55/24)
      - Saz, Natalia (Box-folder 55/25)
      - Schnabel, Karl Ulrich (Box-folder 55/26)
      - Simon, Zoltán (Box-folder 55/27)
      - Stuckenschmid, H. H. (Box-folder 55/28)
      - Viertel, Salka (Box-folder 55/29)
      - Weiser, Peter (Box-folder 55/30)
      - Zweig, Fritz (Box-folder 55/31)
  - Clippings (Box 56, 106)
    Contains newspaper clippings, programs, articles, typescripts, and miscellaneous materials, some photocopied, in English, German, and Dutch.
    Arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Klemperer, Otto (Box-folder 56/1)
    - New York Times (Box-folder 56/2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 56/3)
    - Miscellaneous: in Dutch (Box-folder 106/7)
    - Miscellaneous: not selected (Box-folder 56/4)
    - Miscellaneous: selected (Box-folder 56/5)
  - Lists of Cities and Concerts (Box 56)
    Contains typescripts and carbon copies with emendations in Dutch.
    - Lists of cities and concerts (Box-folder 56/6)
  - Production Materials (Box 57-63, 107)
    Contains programs, photocopies of programs and book title pages, typescripts, newspaper clippings, and black and white photographs of musicians, authors, politicians, city scenes, buildings, and operatic productions.
    Arranged numerically.
    - II A - II F (Box-folder 57/1-15)
    - III A - III E (Box-folder 57/16-20)
    - III F (Box-folder 58/1)
    - IV A - IV B (Box-folder 58/2-4)
    - V ABC - V O (Box-folder 58/5-14)
    - VI - VI H (Box-folder 59/1-20)
    - VI JK - VI AZ (Box-folder 60/1-13)
    - VII A - VII F (Box-folder 60/14-21)
    - VII F - VII extra (Box-folder 61/1-20)
    - VIII A - VIII B (Box-folder 61/21-25)
    - VIII B - VIII T (Box-folder 62/1-14)
    - IX A - X, C (Box-folder 62/15-18)
    - X E - X extra (Box-folder 63/1-9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 63/10-15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 107/1-3)
  - Index Cards (Box 64-84)
    Identifies photographs used in and considered for the film; in English, German, and Dutch.
    Arranged alphabetically by type.
    - Chronological, 1900-1955 (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 65)
    - Names, A-Z (Box 66)
    - Places, A-Z (Box 67)
    - Production materials. Black
      - VII A and miscellaneous (Box 68)
      - VII D - VII Y (Box 69)
      - VI F and miscellaneous (Box 70)
      - VI, VII (Box 75)
    - Production materials. Blue
      - I B - X M extra (Box 71)
      - VI A - X B (Box 72)
      - VIII A and miscellaneous (Box 73)
      - VIII R - X D (Box 74)
      - X, V (Box 75)
    - Production materials. Pink (Box 81-82)
    - Production materials. Purple
      - II - III (Box 76)
      - IV - VI (Box 77)
      - VI continued (Box 78-79)
      - VII (Box 80)
      - VII continued; verso VIII (Box 81)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 83-84)
  - Iconography (Box 85-100, 106, 108)
    Contains photoprints, contact prints, slides, negatives, and microforms used in and considered for the film.
    Photoprints arranged alphabetically by name or by subject; contact prints arranged numerically; slides and microforms arranged alphabetically by subject; negatives arranged numerically, followed by alphabetical arrangement by subject.
    - Photoprints
      - Berlin; Strassburg (Box-folder 85/1)
      - Boulez, Pierre (Box-folder 85/2)
      - Covent Garden (Box-folder 85/3)
      - Filmed (Box-folder 85/4-5)
      - Klemperer, Otto (Box-folder 108/4-9)
      - Klemperer, Otto (Box-folder 100/3)
      - Klemperer, Otto (Box-folder 85/6-9)
      - Klemperer, Otto, by Maria Austria (Box-folder 85/10)
      - Klemperer, Otto, by Werner Neumeister (Box-folder 85/11A)
      - Klemperer, Otto with Stravinsky, ca. 1928 (Box-folder 85/11B)
      - Kölnisches Stadtmuseum (Box-folder 85/12)
      - Märkisches Museum (Box-folder 85/13)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 85/14-15)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 108/10-11)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 86/1)
      - Miscellaneous-not filmed (Box-folder 86/2-3)
      - Miscellaneous: Otto Klemperer, festival week, Houden, cityscapes (Box-folder 86/4)
      - Museum/library reproductions (Box-folder 86/5)
      - Österreichische Nationalbibliotek (Box-folder 86/6)
      - Revised film (Box-folder 86/7-9)
      - Schönberg, Arnold: certificate (Box-folder 108/2-3)
      - Saz, Natalia (Box-folder 86/10)
      - Die Zauberflöte (Box-folder 86/11)
    - Contact Prints
      - 1-99 (Box-folder 87/1)
      - 100-178 (Box-folder 87/2)
      - I-XXVII (Box-folder 87/3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 88)
    - Slides
      - Miscellaneous (Box 88)
      - Wien (Box 88)
    - Negatives
      - 1, 5-34 (Box 89)
      - 35-59 (Box 90)
      - 60-83 (Box 91)
      - 84-109 (Box 92)
      - 110-133 (Box 93)
      - 134-159 (Box 94)
      - 160-190 (Box 95)
      - I - XI, XXIII - XXVI, Miscellaneous (Box 96)
      - B - Zauberflöte (Box-folder 97/1-80)
      - Bristol - Zauberflöte (Box-folder 98/1-27)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 100/4-14)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 106/8)
    - Microforms
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 99/1-4)
- Books, 1901-1988 (Box 109-111, Open shelves)
  Contains selected books, either inscribed, signed, or annotated by Otto or Lotte Klemperer. Some books contained letters, newspaper clippings, programs, and photographs. These items and/or photocopies of inscriptions, signatures, and annotations are filed in boxes 109-111. The books themselves are shelved according to call number.
  Arranged alphabetically by author, and title therein.
  - Complete list of books (Box-folder 109/1)
  - Original laid in material and photocopies of annotated pages from books (Box-folder 109/2-111/5)
  - Ernst Bloch: vier Ansprachen anlässlich der Verleihung des Friedenspreises des deutschen Buchhandels. Frankfurt am Main: Börsenverein des deutschen Buchhandels, 1967., Inscribed and signed by E. Jacobi.; Laid in: one program; two newspaper clippings (one inscribed and signed by E. Jacobi).; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Missale Romanum. Harlemi: Joannis H. Gottmer, 1950. (Box-folder 110/4)
    Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1958.
    Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4.
  - Anderson, Martin, ed. Klemperer on Music. London: Toccata Press, 1986., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer. Laid in: typed notes of errata by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Aristainetos. Erotische Briefe. Translated by Albin Lesky. Zürich: Artemis, 1951., Signed by Otto Klemperer; inscribed by unidentified person.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Attila, Boros. Klemperer magyarországon. Budapest: Zenemükiadó, 1973., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Augustinus. Bekenntnisse und Gottesstaat. (Box-folder 109/2)
    Signed by Otto Klemperer; no title page.
    Copy in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2.
  - Bihlmeyer, Pius, ed. Das Messbuch der heiligen Kirche, lateinisch und deutsch. Freiburg im Breisgau: Herder & Co., 1930., Inscribed and signed by Werner Klemperer, 1931.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Bloch, Ernst. Erbschaft dieser Zeit. Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1962., Inscribed and signed by Ernst Bloch.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Bloch, Ernst. Freiheit und Ordnung, abriss der sozial-utopien. New York: Aurora, 1946., Inscribed and signed by Ernst Bloch.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Bloch, Ernst. Literarische Aufsätze. Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1965. (Box-folder 109/2)
    Inscribed and signed by Ernst Bloch.
    Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2.
  - Bloch, Ernst. Naturrecht und menschliche Würde. Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1961., Inscribed and signed by Ernst Bloch.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Bloch, Ernst. Zur Philosophie der Musik. Frankfurt am Main: Suhrkamp, 1974., Inscribed and signed by Ernst Bloch.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 2. (Box-folder 109/2)
  - Bloch, Karola. Aus meinem Leben. Pfullingen: Günther Neske, 1981., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer. Inscribed and signed by Karola Bloch, Nov. 1981.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder3. (Box-folder 109/3)
  - Bloch, Karola. "Denken heisst Überschreiten:" in memoriam Ernst Bloch 1885-1977. Edited by Adelbert Reif. Köln; Frankfurt am Main: Europäische Verlagsanstalt, 1978. (Box-folder 109/3)
    Inscribed and signed by Karola Bloch.
    Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 3.
  - Brion, Marcel. Mozarts Meisteropern. Translated by Hans Kühner. Erlenbach-Zürich and Stuttgart: Eugen Rentsch, 1956., Inscribed and signed.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 3. (Box-folder 109/3)
  - Craft, Robert. Current convictions: views and reviews. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1977., Inscribed and signed by Robert Craft.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 4. (Box-folder 109/4)
  - Dessau, Paul. Notizen zu Noten. Edited by Fritz Hennenberg. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam jun., 1974., Inscribed.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 4. (Box-folder 109/4)
  - Diderot, Denis. Die Nonne. Berlin: Volk und Welt, 1956. (Box-folder 109/4)
    Signed by Otto Klemperer.
    Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 4.
  - Einstein, Alfred. Mozart: sein Charakter, sein Werk. Frankfurt/Main: S. Fischer, 1968., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.; Laid in: printed copy of magazine article, "The First Pamina" by Alfons Rosenberg.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 4. (Box-folder 109/4)
  - Fábián, Imre. Ernster Dezsö. Budapest: Zenemükiadó, 1969., Signed.; Laid in: photocopy of typed article.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5. (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Fleischer, Herbert. Strawinsky. Berlin: Russischer Musikverlag, 1931., Inscribed and signed by Herbert Fleischer.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5. (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Fontane, Theodor. Effi Briest. Berlin: S. Fischer, 1919. (Box-folder 109/5)
    Laid in: newspaper clipping.
    Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5.
  - Freud, Anna. Difficulties in the path of psychoanalysis; a confrontation of past with present viewpoints. New York: International Universities Press, Inc., 1969., Inscribed and signed by Anna Freud.; Copies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5. (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Furtwängler, Elisabeth. Über Wilhelm Furtwängler. Wiesbaden: Brockhaus, 1979., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: printed newspaper clipping in German dated 1979 Nov. 16.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5. (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Galkin, Elliott W. A history of orchestral conducting in theory and practice. New York: Pendragon Press, 1988., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: typed note by Lotte Klemperer, glued to inside front cover.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 5. (Box-folder 109/5)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von. Goethes Briefe an Frau von Stein. Edited by Julius Petersen. Leipzig: Insel-Verlag, 1909. (Box-folder 111/1)
    Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1948.
    Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 111/Folder 1.
  - Gogol, N. W. Tschitschikows Reiseerlebnisses oder die toten Seelen. Translated by H. Röhl. Leipzig: Im-Insel Verlag, n.d., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Gogol, Nikolai. Ukrainische Geschichten. Translated by Alexander Eliasberg. Weimar: Gustav Kiepenheuer, 1917., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Gordon, D. J., ed. Fritz Saxl, 1890-1948: a memoir. London: T. Nelson, n.d., Signed.; Laid in: photocopy of newspaper clippings.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Grass, Günter. Hundejahre. Berlin: Luchterhand, 1963. (Box-folder 109/6)
    Annotated by Otto Klemperer.
    Copies of annotated pages filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6.
  - Grubb, Suvi Raj. Music makers on record. London: Hamish Hamilton, 1986., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: typed errata sheet by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Gulliver, Lemuel. Travels into several remote nations of the world. London: Hayward and Moore, n.d., Laid in: manuscript note in German.; Photocopy filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Harewood, George Henry Hubert Lascelles, Earl of. The tongs and the bones: the memoirs of Lord Harewood. London: Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1981., Signed.; Laid in: newspaper clippings of book review 1981 Oct. 23.; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Hebbel, Friedrich. Gedichte. Edited by Hans Vetter. Stuttgart: Strecker und Schröder, 1924. (Box-folder 109/6)
    Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6.
  - Heine, Heinrich. Zeitungsberichte über Musik und Malerei. Edited by Michael Mann. Frankfurt am Main: Im Insel-Verlag, 1964., Inscribed and signed by Michael Mann.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Henning, Max, trans. Der Koran. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam jun., 1901., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1958.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 2. (Box-folder 110/2)
  - Heyworth, Peter, ed. Conversations with Klemperer. London: Victor Gollancz Ltd., 1973., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: photocopy of typed errata sheet by Lotte Klemperer, filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 109/Folder 6. (Box-folder 109/6)
  - Hirschmann, Ira. Caution to the winds. New York: David McKay Co., Inc., 1962. (Box-folder 110/1)
    Inscribed and signed by Ira Hirschmann.
    Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1.
  - Höcker, Karla, ed. Wilhelm Furtwängler: Dokumente - Berichte und Bilder - Aufzeichnungen. Berlin: Rembrandt, 1968., Annotated in pencil.; Photocopy filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Hoffmann, E. T. A. E. T. A. Hoffmanns musikalische Schriften. Edited by Edgar Istel., Inscribed and signed by Robert Marse, July 1921.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Hoffmann, E. T. A. Fantasiestücke in Callot's Manier. Edited by Eduard Grisebach. Leipzig: Max Hesses, n.d., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Homer. Ilias/Odyssee. Edited by Johann Voss and Johann Heinrich. München: Winkler, n.d. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. Albert Schweitzer und die Musik. Wiesbaden: Breitkopf & Härtel, 1975., Inscribed and signed by Erwin R. Jacobi.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - James, Burnett. Beethoven and human destiny. London: Phoenix House, 1960., Laid in: typed, signed letter from Burnett James, 1960 June 21.; Photocopies and original filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Jefferson, Alan. Lotte Lehmann 1888-1976. London: Julia MacRae Books, 1988., Laid in: annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopy of typed letter by Lotte Klemperer dated 1989 Feb. 14 annotated in hand of Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies and original filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Kafka, Franz. Hochzeitsvorbereitungen auf dem Lande und andere Prosa aus dem Nachlass. New York: Schocken Books, 1953., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Kant, Immanuel. Die drei Kritiken in ihrem Zusammenhang mit dem Gesamtwerk. Stuttgart: Alfred Kröner, 1956., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Keller, Gottfried. Gesammelte Gedichte, erster Band. Stuttgart/Berlin: J. G. Cott'sche Buchhandlung, n.d., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Keller, Werner. Und wurden zerstreut unter alle Völker: die nachbiblische Geschichte des jüdischen Volkes. München/Zürich: Droemer Knaur, 1966., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1967.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Kempen, Thomas von. Das Buch von der Nachfolge Christi. Translated by Joh. Mich. Sailer. Freiburg im Breisgau: Herdersche Verlagshandlung, 1916., Inscribed.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Kempen, Thomas von. Vier Bücher der Nachfolge Christi. Edited by Adolf Donders. Kevelaer: Butzon & Bercker, 1934., Signed by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 1. (Box-folder 110/1)
  - Klemperer, Lotte. Die Personalakten der Johanna Geisler eine Dokumentation in Stichproben. Frankfurt/Main: Fischer Taschenbuch, 1983., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 2. (Box-folder 110/2)
  - Kokoschka, Oskar. Briefe IV, 1953-1976. Edited by Olda Kokoschka and Heinz Spielmann. Düsseldorf: Claasen, 1988., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: postcard signed by Olda Kokoschka.; Photocopies and original filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 2. (Box-folder 110/2)
  - Landauer, Gustav. Shakespeare. Edited by Martin Buber. Hamburg: Rütten & Loening, 1962., Annotated and signed by Otto Klemperer, 1962.; Laid in: magazine article, Nov. 1974.; Photocopies and original filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 2. (Box-folder 110/2)
  - Mahler, Gustav. Briefe, 1879-1911. Edited by Alma Mahler. Berlin/Wien/Leipzig: Paul Zsolnay, 1924., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Signed by Otto Klemperer, 1946.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Mann, Erika and Klaus Mann. Rundherum. Das Abenteuer einer Weltreise. München: Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung, 1965., Laid in: inscribed and signed card by Erika Mann taped to front page.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Mann, Golo. Wallenstein: sein Leben erzählt. Frankfurt am Main: S. Fischer, 1971., Signed by Golo Mann.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Markun, Silvia, ed. Ernst Bloch in Selbstzeugnissen und Bilddokumenten. Reinbek bei Hamburg: Rowohlt, 1977., Annotated and inscribed by Lotte Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Mayer, Reinhold, ed. and trans. Der babylonische Talmud. München: Wilhelm Goldmann, 1963., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 3. (Box-folder 110/3)
  - Morgenstern, Soma. Die Blutsäule; Zeichen und Wunder am Sereth. Wien/Stuttgart/Zürich: Hans Deutsch, 1964., Signed by Soma Morgenstern.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Morgenstern, Soma. Der Sohn des verlorenen Sohnes. Berlin: Erich Reiss, 1935., Inscribed and signed by Soma Morgenstern, 1936.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Morgenstern, Soma. The third pillar. Translated by Ludwig Lewisohn. New York: Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, 1955., Inscribed and signed by Soma Morgenstern, 1957.; Laid in: newspaper clipping glued to inside front cover.; Photocopies filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Newlin, Dika. Schoenberg remembered: diaries and recollections (1938-1976). New York: Pendragon Press, 1980., Annotated by Lotte Klemperer.; Laid in: photograph and three newspaper clippings (one photocopy).; Photocopies and originals filed in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)
  - Nietzsche, Friedrich. Die Unschuld des Werdens; der Nachlass. Edited by Alfred Baeumler. Leipzig: Alfred Kröner, 1931., Annotated by Otto Klemperer.; Photocopies in Otto Klemperer Archive, Box 110/Folder 4. (Box-folder 110/4)